JIM: Previously on Gotham...
- I set a bomb.
- Thousands of people could die.
HUGO: Yes. But paying
that price will be better
than releasing
what's down there...
(GROWLING)
Are you ready to play?
Wayne Enterprises runs Indian
Hill, but who runs Wayne Enterprises?
BRUCE: There's a
secret council in Gotham.
It's them that wanted me dead.
We're so close to
the ultimate truth.
(YELLING)
James.
You did a very bad thing to me.
And now you're going to...
- (BLOWS)
- (GASPS)
- Impossible.
- (TUTTING) Nothing is impossible.
(SNARLING)
Thank you.
Bruce, I might not
see you for a while.
Where are you going?
I have to find Lee.
(DR. THOMPKINS LAUGHING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(ALARM BLARING)
MAN: Hello?
We're closed.
If you leave now I
won't call the cops.
(OBJECTS CLATTERING)
(GROWLING)
(SCREAMING)
JIM: Hey.
Any chance you
wanna come quietly?
(GROWLING)
(JIM GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
(LAUGHS)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
- (CAMERAS CLICKING)
- (INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
At 8:15 this evening,
an individual robbed a
pharmacy and attacked its owner.
While we don't
have an ID as yet,
we believe that this individual is
another escapee from Indian Hill.
How much do you know
about other escapees?
FEMALE REPORTER 1: Are
these monsters dangerous?
FEMALE REPORTER 2:
Captain Barnes! Captain Barnes!
Valerie Vale, Gotham Gazette.
Why can't we see the escapee?
Because crews are still
picking up the pieces.
This isn't the first time that a bounty
hunter has apprehended an escapee.
Is the GCPD incapable of
handling this threat themselves?
Whoa. Only a handful of these escapees
have been brought in by bounty hunters.
The vast majority were
apprehended by GCPD.
Yes. True that.
Excuse me. Excuse me. I
take issue with the word "threat."
These escapees are themselves
victims of Hugo Strange.
Now, if any ordinary,
hard-working citizen
wants to help get these
poor souls off the street
so that they may
receive proper treatment,
well, these citizens
should be lauded.
And rewarded financially.
Mr. James, before they
were taken to Indian Hill,
these "poor souls" were
all criminally insane inmates
at Arkham Asylum, were they not?
Next question.
Hear that? You should be lauded.
I'll settle for the cash.
How many escapees have
you brought in now, hmm? Six?
Five grand a pop,
that's not too bad.
What happens when
there aren't any more?
I don't think Gotham's running
out of monsters anytime soon.
I really can't get you
to come back, huh?
Look, whatever happened
when you went to see Lee,
and you know I
don't like to pry...
Sure you do.
That's because you
won't tell me anything.
The whole point is, man's
not supposed to be alone.
You have a family here.
Can't do it, Harv.
But you've got no problem
chasing down Strange's freaks.
Yeah. It pays the rent.
You are a cop in
everything but name.
Yeah. Except I don't
have to listen to Barnes.
I get to go home when I
want. Get drunk when I want.
And at the end of the day, I sleep, 'cause
saving Gotham's not my job anymore.
Jim, I love you like a brother.
But you've got to
stop blaming the job
for what happened
between you and Lee.
And do you really think I
don't get drunk when I want?
(CHUCKLES)
Detective Bullock, I looked into
the drug the escapee was after.
It's a powerful immune
suppressant. Gordon.
See, look at Lucius here,
our new resident expert
on all things scientific.
He said sayonara to the
Wayne Enterprises robots, hmm?
And he loves it here.
Wayne Enterprises revealed
itself as morally corrupt.
Here, despite the
primitive facilities,
casual violence, fascistic
meathead culture...
Lucius.
I love it.
Anyway, that drug is only sold
at three pharmacies in the city.
And the other two pharmacies
were both robbed in the last month.
Question is why are Indian Hill
escapees now robbing pharmacies?
BULLOCK: Good question.
So what do you say,
just like the old days,
you and me run it
together, huh, partner?
You get a hard lead on an escapee,
and the price is right, I'll bring him in.
Thanks for the drink. Lucius.
"Fascistic meathead culture"?
I mean, you couldn't try to
be just a little bit more positive?
- I was very positive.
- Uh-huh.
Why is Hugo Strange the
only one that's been arrested?
The situation...
What about the rumors that Indian
Hill is a Wayne Enterprise facility?
And how many more of
these escapees are at large?
Are we talking 20? Thirty? Come
on, just give me a blink if I'm close.
The situation is firmly in hand.
MAN: Liar!
Oh, no.
My name is Oswald Cobblepot.
We know who you are,
Penguin. What do you want?
COBBLEPOT: What do I want?
I want you to tell the truth
to the people of Gotham.
They would have us believe
that there is no danger.
But I was there the night those
creatures broke out of Indian Hill.
I saw them.
And I saw who was leading them.
Are you saying the
escapees are organized?
Hello. That is what I am saying.
There is absolutely
nothing to support that.
I told the police
who to look for.
I begged them. Time and again.
And they have done nothing.
So, I am here to speak directly
to the good people of Gotham.
The enemy's name is Fish Mooney.
BARNES: Fish Mooney? She hasn't
been spotted for over six months.
She's either long
gone, or she's dead.
I wish I shared
your simple belief.
She is a criminal.
She is a murderer.
And now, God knows what kind of
monster Hugo Strange has turned her into.
I implore every
citizen of Gotham.
If you love your family,
if you love your children,
find Fish Mooney.
Until then, no one is safe.
(REPORTERS CHATTERING)
MAN: Hey, Penguin.
Hello, Jim.
Oswald.
I'm surprised you
haven't found Mooney.
I hear you're quite the
bounty hunter these days.
You haven't made
it worth my while.
Oh, tough guy now.
But he makes a point.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Ozzie, Butch.
What a nice surprise.
Forgive me for
not coming sooner.
- The place looks marvelous.
- Hmm.
Wouldn't you say so, Butch?
Yeah. Place looks great.
I imagine you're here about your offer,
to let us shelter under your umbrella?
I only want what's best for you.
I appreciate the thought.
But we're big girls.
We can handle ourselves.
Can't we?
Sure we can.
Hey, Butch.
Hey. How're you doing?
You taking care of yourself?
Yeah. Yeah. So,
how're you doing?
You already asked her that.
(CLEARS THROAT) Listen, you
guys should take him up on his offer.
Gotham's full of
rough characters.
You look great. By the way.
Wait over there. Please.
Poor bunny. Break-ups are hard.
I offered to kill you.
I thought it would
raise his spirits,
and would be my pleasure seeing
as how you murdered my mother!
But he is nursing some foolish hope
that you two will get back together.
Love.
You can take your
offer and stick it...
We'll think about it, Ozzie.
Fine.
But that's not the
only reason I'm here.
Spread the word.
I want Fish Mooney,
and I will give a million dollars
to whoever can bring her to me.
Dead, or alive.
Chopped into pieces.
I want her.
You okay, Butch?
World getting you down?
Uh, I am fine, kid.
And you're too young
to be in here. Scram.
Yeesh. Just trying to be nice.
Just seein' her
kills me. You know?
Get over it.
And that child just
stole your wallet.
(CAT YOWLING)
Hey.
Barbara and that whip
lady are gonna get angry,
you stealing from
their customers.
Let 'em. I've got
other things goin'.
- Like what?
- Top secret.
Let's eat. I'm starving.
Hey, kid. Take it. It's yours.
You keep feeding strays, and
one's gonna follow you home.
Like you? Come on.
Well, that should
be the last of it.
I'll put the kettle on.
There is nothing like
a sweet cup of tea
to make home feel like
home after a long trip away.
Eh, Master Bruce?
You all right?
Were we right to leave, Alfred?
Stay away all of this time?
Well, considering the
appalling state of the topiary,
I should say
absolutely-bloody-not.
Alfred, you know what I mean.
I know you know why we left.
We had to leave.
You're nervous about
tomorrow, aren't ya'?
Yes.
Well, you wouldn't be
human if you weren't.
So, why don't you go through
there, take a pew. Help your feet up.
And I'll see about that
lovely cup of tea. All right?
Saving that for someone special?
Coffee please.
"Search continues for new
Arkham Asylum director."
Right. Good luck finding
anyone to take that job.
I'm Valerie Vale.
Reporter for the Gazette.
I know who you are.
And you're James Gordon.
Son of a respected Gotham DA.
Former war hero. Former white
knight cop. Now bounty hunter.
You know, someone
should do a story on you.
Not interested.
Yeah. Me neither, actually.
You were there that
night, at Indian Hill.
I've got nothing to say.
What about the fact that besides
Hugo Strange and his assistant,
no one else has been arrested?
Or that despite everything
pointing to Wayne Enterprises,
there seems to be
zero investigation.
You're new to
Gotham, aren't you?
Okay. This is where you tell
me things work differently here?
I'm not from Gotham. But my
dad's a cop. My brothers are cops.
And things work the
same everywhere.
I was going to say, it's hard
to find a quiet bar in this city.
I like coming here. Please
don't make me find another.
Now, do you think
Cobblepot's right,
that Fish Mooney's
organizing the escapees?
Penguin is a liar
and a murderer.
Hmm. But?
But, based on the escapees,
and knowing Fish, I hope not.
Well, he's offering a million
dollars to whoever brings her in.
You're welcome.
It's a puzzle.
The trick is opening it.
The man at the store said it's
one of the most difficult ever made.
People pass it down
unsolved for generations.
A mathematician
once went mad trying...
Yes.
Well, there you go. (LAUGHS)
It was a lovely thought.
And did you get the biscuits?
And the sweater? I know
how drafty these rooms are.
- Mr. Penguin...
- Oswald.
- When I think how I treated you...
- Stop.
Why are you being so kind?
Talking to you
these past months,
I don't know how I
would've gotten by otherwise.
With Fish out there
planning who knows what.
Me being surrounded
by morons and lunatics.
I know the feeling.
Why didn't she kill me
when she had the chance?
I was powerless.
She must have a larger goal. I
need to know what she is doing.
Do you?
When Alexander
encountered the Gordian knot,
a knot so complex no one had
ever been able to untangle it,
he just removed his sword
and cut it in two. (CHUCKLES)
Details can be distracting.
Sometimes, a
simple solution is best.
So no matter what
she is planning,
just remember...
Penguins eat fish.
You know why we're here.
What are you doing
here? Stop. Stop.
(GASPS)
So, what are we after? It's
not like they keep cash around.
For now, survival.
Don't move.
Hands.
Of course.
Drop the gun.
Now knock yourself out.
That was awesome. How did you...
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Fish.
I'm fine. Watch the door.
Yeah, that's the only company
that makes the drug. Fray Pharma.
They actually have a
warehouse here in Gotham.
You think they
could be a target?
JIM: Yeah, they're the only
pharmacy that carries the drug.
If somebody wants it, they'll
have to go to the source.
Let me find the address.
That's all right.
James Gordon.
Hands where I can see 'em.
So, what?
You're here to collect the bounty
that Penguin has over my head?
What is it, a million dollars?
And to think I
let that punk live.
Well then, I think
you'd better cuff me.
Cuff yourself.
How many others
you have with you?
They're all with me.
Every wretched soul that
Hugo Strange experimented on.
But tonight, just him.
(GRUNTING)
Did you hear them rats last
night, scurrying around in the attic?
Drove me bloody-bonkers.
Now, may I ask you, what's
the point of having a caretaker
if they can't take
care of nothing, eh?
You all right, Master B?
Hungry. I should've eaten.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
I do this, there's
no turning back.
No.
You say your piece.
We'll see about getting you
a proper breakfast, all right?
I'd like to thank the board
for giving me this time.
It will come as no surprise
I'd like to talk about Indian Hill.
I know preliminary investigations have
concluded Hugo Strange acted alone.
I reject this conclusion.
While trapped in Indian
Hill, I was led to believe
an unnamed group had
taken control of my company,
and it was they who
hired Hugo Strange.
I left Gotham both
for my own safety,
and so that I might have the time to
discover hard evidence of their existence.
(SCOFFS) A conspiracy
theory? That's why we're all here?
Excuse me, Master Bruce.
Pardon me, sir. Might I
have your name please?
- What?
- Your name. Please, sir.
Crowley.
Mr. Crowley, did your parents
never teach you any manners?
I don't have to listen to this.
Oh, but you do, sir.
That is precisely the
point that I am making.
I know how it sounds.
But I now have proof they exist.
And I can tell you
that they're here.
In this room.
I want to talk face-to-face.
You have 24 hours to contact me,
or the information that I've gathered
will be sent to every newspaper
and television station in Gotham.
Thank you for your time.
- Pancakes?
- Pancakes.
WOMAN: And how
did the board react?
Then he leaves us no choice.
Bruce Wayne.
Do it quietly.
(WHISTLES)
- You Barbara Kean?
- We're closed.
What?
You built this club
on our territory.
We let you 'cause we
heard Penguin had your back.
And now we hear that ain't so.
Oh.
Bad for you. Good for us.
Get the hell out.
(BARBARA GRUNTS)
This place is ours now.
Do you understand?
You can't just come in here...
Don't hit me, okay? Please.
(SOBBING)
(LAUGHING)
(GRUNTS)
- Hey.
You still paying for stuff
about the Indian Hill freaks?
Depends. If it's good.
Is Fish Mooney good?
Guess I'm finding a new bar.
I heard you ran into
Fish Mooney yesterday.
So?
So, are you still
interested in finding her?
Every cop in the city
is looking for her now.
But I know where
she's gonna be next.
And why are you telling me?
You see, I need
something from the cops.
They're not gonna tell me.
But Bullock still trusts you.
And you want me to lie to him.
A million dollars
covers a lot of sins.
And obviously, I
get to come along.
Aw, don't tell me you
have a conscience?
Yeah, all right.
Jimmy. Hey.
So, after your run-in with Fish,
Barnes had us up all night,
rousting her old hideouts.
Yeah. Did you find anything?
Nada. But I did get
what you asked for.
You wanna tell me
what this is about?
It's a hunch. Probably nothing.
Look, if you've got a hot
lead you don't wanna share
so you can collect Penguin's
million, I got no problem with that.
Just don't get yourself
killed or me fired, okay?
I'll do my best. Hey.
Get some rest, huh?
Hey.
When did you get back?
A couple days ago.
I tried to find
you before I left.
No worries.
You remember what I
discovered that night at Indian Hill,
that there was a secret group
that had infiltrated my company.
I wasn't paying attention.
I needed time to research
them. I couldn't do it here.
Okay.
I have a plan, but these
people are powerful.
We need to assume they
know you and I are friends.
- You need to be careful.
- Got it.
- I'm serious.
- I can see that.
I'm sorry I was
gone for so long.
Don't apologize.
Shoot, if I could fly to Italy and
eat pizza all day I would, too.
- Switzerland.
- Italy's better.
- Selina...
- Bruce, seriously.
Don't sweat it.
I gotta go. I'll see you around.
Good to see you, Selina.
- Hey, did you get her?
- Yeah.
She was under guard in a
building on Douglas and 80th.
There's one thing though.
Hey. Hey! What the
hell are you doing?
You're a hundred yards
from a police station.
I'll be back in an hour or two.
We had a deal.
If there's a story, I'll
make sure you get it.
Oh, you're a son of a bitch.
Also, you could scream, but then
you'd have to tell the cops everything,
and you'd lose
the story entirely.
Gordon. Gordon!
You son of a bitch.
Forty-Seven, this is dispatch.
FEMALE OFFICER:
This is Forty-Seven.
Report to Captain
Barnes immediately.
Relief team will take
your place. Over and out.
You got it. We're out of here.
(SIREN BLARING)
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
I knocked.
I didn't answer.
You alone?
All day, every day.
I wasn't expecting
Jim Gordon to stop by.
You aren't supposed
to be here, are you?
How come you're not in jail?
I agreed to testify
against Professor Strange.
In case you're about to ask, I
don't know who really ran Indian Hill.
I don't care who
ran Indian Hill.
Then why are you here?
Fish Mooney.
And why would I know
how to find Fish Mooney?
No reason you would.
But it's clear whatever you and
Strange did to her is making her sick.
Her people are stealing drugs,
but I don't think they're working.
She's gonna come after you.
Or her goons will, and
they'll lead me to her.
And how will they find me? Only
the police are supposed to know.
My guess, she'll have someone
get the information for her.
Someone who wouldn't suspect
being used. Maybe a reporter.
She will follow that person, or
whoever she goes to for help.
In this case, a bounty
hunter, right to you.
(DOOR SQUEAKING)
You led them to me on
purpose. You're using me as bait.
I don't like being played. Plus,
she's worth a million dollars.
No! Gordon, help!
Somebody, help!
I don't know which one of you I wanna
bat over the head with this cane more.
I get it.
Life disappointed you.
So what? Does that
make you special?
I'm done with you.
You cross me again,
I will have you skinned alive
and your head put on a pike.
And you.
When I came back, I saw the way
you handled things while I was away.
I swear, I had this
feeling right here.
I thought I was
having a heart attack.
But it was pride,
Bullock. In you.
The next time I have that
feeling, I'll know it was just gas.
You both better
pray that we find her.
Get out of my sight.
(COUGHING)
I'd say that went well.
He was right though.
About me being Captain.
I did a good job.
I even liked it.
Yeah. Hey, look, I'm sorry, Harvey.
I'll do my best to find Peabody.
Honestly, Jim,
for the time being,
it might be better if
you just stayed away.
Hey. Hey!
Ow.
- Just tell me. Did you know?
- Did I know what?
That Mooney was
using us to find Peabody.
You mean using you?
Yeah, it's her kind of play.
- You should've told me.
- Sure.
Why didn't you tell me
who your source was?
That's it? You're not
gonna try and find Mooney?
Barnes is on it. I've had a
long day. I'm gonna get a drink.
Gordon.
Nothing.
- Come on.
- I said no.
- Who are they?
- Just people.
They need me to
do things for them.
Well, I can do stuff.
These are scary people,
okay? It's for your own good.
You just don't wanna share.
Just stay here, all right?
Hello.
What do you want?
I want to talk to her.
I was following her.
She was kind to me.
But then, she met him, that boy.
What happened to you?
You know me?
Uh, yeah. I know Bruce Wayne.
Who is he? Who is he?
What's wrong with
you? Let go of me.
Bruce Wayne. Bruce
Wayne. Who is he?
I really do not
have time for this.
- He started it.
- BORIS: It's a lie.
The cwub is on our territory.
"Cwub"? What's a "cwub"?
Cwub.
What's a "cwub"? I mean,
can anyone understand him?
- Do you know what a "cwub" is?
- Cwub.
Enough!
We will work something out.
Now, this is his territory. What
are you willing to give him?
Boop. (CHUCKLES)
That is not helpful.
Are you telling me you don't
see what's going on here?
He is behind this.
What're you talking about?
He sent this ding
dong to squeeze us,
hoping it would
send us back to you,
so that he could lord it
over Tabby. Ain't that right?
(SCOFFS) That's
just... That's crazy.
She's crazy. She
was in Arkham, hello?
Hello? So was I.
Is that true, Butch?
Unbelievable.
Fine. Run your club.
Just so we're clear,
the only reason you
are alive is Butch.
The moment he gives
me the word, you're mine.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
(SNARLING)
Hello again.
I know why you brought me here.
Your body is beginning to reject
the changes we made to your DNA.
You feel it every time
you use your ability.
How do I fix it?
Stop using the power.
Every time you use it,
new cells are activated,
and your body rejects them.
Stop, and you will recover.
It's that simple.
It's just...
I like the new me.
I can't fix you. I can't
re-order your DNA.
There's always a way.
Strange. He can.
- He's the only one.
- (GROANS)
Where is Strange?
I don't know.
They've hidden him
somewhere secret.
Him fixing me is
just the beginning.
I want an army.
I want an army like me!
And he is going
to give it to me.
- He can't.
- Oh, he will.
Or he will die.
You remember Marv.
He's one of yours.
Sort of a fountain
of youth in reverse.
(GASPS, WHIMPERS)
Good night, Ethel.
(WHIMPERING)
(GROANING)
We caught a spy.
- Ivy?
- Selina.
Tell this creep to let go of me.
She's my friend.
- I don't like spies.
- She's not a spy.
Ivy, what're you doing here?
I followed you the other day,
so I knew where you went.
Bruce Wayne came looking for
you, but he was acting all weird.
Who else have you told about us?
- No one.
- I asked her.
- Selina...
- Ivy, shut up.
They're those monsters
everyone's talking about, aren't they?
You better tell your friend to be
careful who she calls a monster.
You better stay away
from me. All of you. I'll tell.
Marv.
SELINA: No!
Leave her alone.
IVY: Stay away from me!
Ivy. Ivy!
Ivy!
Watch out!
Help!
(SCREAMS)
(SPLASHING)
Ivy.
(SOBBING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
ALFRED: Right. Once this
alarm is set, Master Bruce,
no coming downstairs till
the morning. Is that clear?
Yes. But was a new alarm
system really necessary?
I don't know. Was it really necessary
offering a challenge to a shadowy cabal?
Yes, it was necessary,
Master Bruce.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
BRUCE: Alfred!
Alfred!
Alfred, wake up. Alfred!
(STRAINING)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
English -SDH